window.quizData = [
  {
    question: "Mangal Pandey belonged to —",
    options: [
      "32nd Bengal Native Infantry",
      "34th Bengal Native Infantry",
      "36th Bengal Native Infantry",
      "38th Bengal Native Infantry",
    ],
    answer: "34th Bengal Native Infantry",
  },

  {
    question: "The Revolt of 1857 started from —",
    options: ["Delhi", "Kanpur", "Meerut", "Lucknow"],
    answer: "Meerut",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Bahadur Shah Zafar and his sons were arrested by British officials from —",
    options: [
      "Red Fort (Delhi)",
      "Humayun’s Tomb (Delhi)",
      "Jama Masjid (Delhi)",
      "Agra Fort",
    ],
    answer: "Humayun’s Tomb (Delhi)",
  },

  {
    question: "Begum Hazrat Mahal led the rebellion of 1857 from —",
    options: ["Delhi", "Kanpur", "Lucknow", "Jhansi"],
    answer: "Lucknow",
  },

  {
    question: "Tantia Tope (Ramchandra Panduranga) was killed in —",
    options: ["1857", "1858", "1859", "1860"],
    answer: "1859",
  },

  {
    question: "Tantia Tope led the revolt of 1857 from —",
    options: ["Jhansi", "Kanpur", "Gwalior", "Lucknow"],
    answer: "Kanpur",
  },

  {
    question: "In 1857, the British suffered defeat in —",
    options: [
      "The Battle of Jhansi",
      "The Battle of Chinha",
      "The Battle of Gwalior",
      "The Battle of Kanpur",
    ],
    answer: "The Battle of Chinha",
  },

  {
    question: "Nana Sahib, a rebel at Kanpur, was the son of Peshwa —",
    options: ["Baji Rao I", "Baji Rao II", "Madhav Rao", "Balaji Vishwanath"],
    answer: "Baji Rao II",
  },

  {
    question: "Veer Kunwar Singh led the Revolt of 1857 in —",
    options: ["Bihar", "Jhansi", "Lucknow", "Delhi"],
    answer: "Bihar",
  },

  {
    question: "Khan Bahadur led the revolt of 1857 from —",
    options: ["Kanpur", "Bareilly", "Delhi", "Gwalior"],
    answer: "Bareilly",
  },

  {
    question: "Which Mughal ruler contributed to the revolt of 1857?",
    options: ["Akbar II", "Bahadur Shah I", "Bahadur Shah II", "Shah Alam II"],
    answer: "Bahadur Shah II",
  },

  {
    question: "Bahadur Shah II was sent to exile in Burma after the —",
    options: [
      "Revolt of 1848",
      "Revolt of 1857",
      "Revolt of 1860",
      "Delhi Uprising of 1856",
    ],
    answer: "Revolt of 1857",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The sepoys of Meerut arrived at the Gates of Red Fort on 11 May 1857 to meet —",
    options: [
      "Nana Sahib",
      "Begum Hazrat Mahal",
      "Bahadur Shah",
      "Tantia Tope",
    ],
    answer: "Bahadur Shah",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Mangal Pandey killed two British officials (Hugeson and Baugh) on —",
    options: [
      "27 March 1857",
      "28 March 1857",
      "29 March 1857",
      "30 March 1857",
    ],
    answer: "29 March 1857",
  },

  {
    question: "Mangal Pandey was hanged on —",
    options: ["6 April 1857", "7 April 1857", "8 April 1857", "9 April 1857"],
    answer: "8 April 1857",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Queen Victoria’s proclamation, marking the beginning of British Crown's administration in India, was made on —",
    options: [
      "31 October 1858",
      "1 November 1858",
      "5 November 1858",
      "15 November 1858",
    ],
    answer: "1 November 1858",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The revolt in the countryside of the Bombay Deccan occurred in —",
    options: ["1857", "1861", "1875", "1882"],
    answer: "1875",
  },

  {
    question: "Sidhu Manjhi was the leader of —",
    options: [
      "Kol Rebellion",
      "Santhal Rebellion",
      "Munda Rebellion",
      "Paika Rebellion",
    ],
    answer: "Santhal Rebellion",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the Revolt of 1857, Shah Mal rebelled at Baraut in Uttar Pradesh and was killed in battle in —",
    options: ["May 1857", "June 1857", "July 1857", "August 1857"],
    answer: "July 1857",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The painting 'In Memoriam', dedicated to British women in India during the Revolt of 1857, was painted by —",
    options: [
      "Joseph Noel Patone",
      "M.F. Pithawala",
      "Thomas Daniell",
      "William Carpenter",
    ],
    answer: "Joseph Noel Patone",
  },

  {
    question: "The Revolt of 1857 was finally suppressed by the British in —",
    options: ["1858", "1859", "1860", "1861"],
    answer: "1859",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Enfield rifles that became the immediate reason for the 1857 revolt were introduced by —",
    options: [
      "British Army",
      "East India Company",
      "Governor-General Dalhousie",
      "Governor-General Canning",
    ],
    answer: "East India Company",
  },

  {
    question: "The region known as the 'Nursery of the Bengal army' was —",
    options: ["Awadh", "Bihar", "Punjab", "Delhi"],
    answer: "Awadh",
  },

  {
    question:
      "During the Santhal Rebellion and the Revolt of 1857, the British were helped by —",
    options: [
      "Raja Ranjit Singh",
      "Maharaja Mehtab Chand",
      "Kunwar Singh",
      "Rani Avantibai",
    ],
    answer: "Maharaja Mehtab Chand",
  },

  {
    question: "Rani Lakshmibai of Jhansi was killed in battle in the year —",
    options: ["1857", "1858", "1859", "1860"],
    answer: "1858",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Revolt of 1857 was called 'Neither first, nor national, nor war of Independence' by —",
    options: ["V.D. Savarkar", "S.N. Sen", "RC Majumdar", "Jawaharlal Nehru"],
    answer: "RC Majumdar",
  },

  {
    question: "The Mughal Emperor deported to Rangoon by the British was —",
    options: [
      "Akbar II",
      "Bahadur Shah Zafar",
      "Shah Alam II",
      "Bahadur Shah I",
    ],
    answer: "Bahadur Shah Zafar",
  },
  {
    question: "The leader of the 1857 Revolt in Ramgarh state was —",
    options: [
      "Rani Lakshmibai",
      "Avantibai Lodhi",
      "Begum Hazrat Mahal",
      "Jhalkari Bai",
    ],
    answer: "Avantibai Lodhi",
  },

  {
    question: "Mangal Pandey belonged to the British Army regiment named —",
    options: [
      "32nd Bengal Native Infantry",
      "34th Bengal Native Infantry",
      "36th Bengal Native Infantry",
      "38th Bengal Native Infantry",
    ],
    answer: "34th Bengal Native Infantry",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Bahadur Shah Zafar was imprisoned in Rangoon jail by the British in the year —",
    options: ["1857", "1858", "1859", "1860"],
    answer: "1858",
  },

  {
    question: "The Indian Revolt of 1857 started on May 10, 1857 from —",
    options: ["Delhi", "Meerut", "Kanpur", "Lucknow"],
    answer: "Meerut",
  },

  {
    question: "The Indian Revolt of 1857 ended in Gwalior on —",
    options: ["10 June 1858", "15 June 1858", "20 June 1858", "25 June 1858"],
    answer: "20 June 1858",
  },

  {
    question: "The Policy of ‘Paramountcy’ was initiated by —",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Canning",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Hastings",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Annexation of Awadh by the British East India Company took place in —",
    options: ["1854", "1855", "1856", "1857"],
    answer: "1856",
  },

  {
    question:
      "A heavy, large-caliber smoothbore gun for infantry soldiers, introduced in the 16th century, was called —",
    options: ["Rifle", "Musket", "Cannon", "Pistol"],
    answer: "Musket",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Rani Lakshmibai died fighting British colonial rulers on 18th June 1858 in —",
    options: ["Jhansi", "Gwalior", "Kanpur", "Lucknow"],
    answer: "Gwalior",
  },

  {
    question: "The siege to the fortress of Jhansi in 1858 was laid by —",
    options: [
      "Colin Campbell",
      "Sir Hugh Rose",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Henry Havelock",
    ],
    answer: "Sir Hugh Rose",
  },

  {
    question: "The Mughal ruler at the time of the Revolt of 1857 was —",
    options: ["Akbar II", "Shah Alam II", "Bahadur Shah Zafar", "Farrukhsiyar"],
    answer: "Bahadur Shah Zafar",
  },

  {
    question: "The leader of Faizabad during the 1857 Revolt was —",
    options: ["Tantia Tope", "Maulvi Ahmadullah", "Nana Sahib", "Kunwar Singh"],
    answer: "Maulvi Ahmadullah",
  },

  {
    question: "The Governor General of India during the 1857 Revolt was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },
  {
    question:
      "During the days of the Revolt of 1857, Maulvi Ahmadullah Shah was known as —",
    options: ["Danka Shah", "Fakir Shah", "Rebel Saint", "Peer-e-Hind"],
    answer: "Danka Shah",
  },

  {
    question: "In Bihar, the Revolt of 1857 was led by —",
    options: [
      "Rani Lakshmibai",
      "Kunwar Singh",
      "Begum Hazrat Mahal",
      "Tantia Tope",
    ],
    answer: "Kunwar Singh",
  },

  {
    question: "The Governor General of India during the Revolt of 1857 was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },

  {
    question: "Rani Laxmibai died in —",
    options: ["Jhansi", "Gwalior", "Kanpur", "Lucknow"],
    answer: "Gwalior",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The tribal leaders Sitaram Kanwar and Raghunath Singh Mandloi Bhilala joined the Anti-British Revolution in the year —",
    options: ["1848 A.D.", "1855 A.D.", "1857 A.D.", "1860 A.D."],
    answer: "1857 A.D.",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Mangal Pandey was hanged in 1857 for attacking British officers in —",
    options: ["Meerut", "Barrackpore", "Delhi", "Kanpur"],
    answer: "Barrackpore",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Third Anglo-Mysore War (1790–92) was fought between the British and —",
    options: ["Hyder Ali", "Tipu Sultan", "Mir Qasim", "Nizam of Hyderabad"],
    answer: "Tipu Sultan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Governor-General of India during the First Anglo-Afghan War was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Ellenborough",
      "Lord Auckland",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Auckland",
  },

  {
    question: "Charles Wood's Dispatch (1854) was related to the —",
    options: [
      "Judicial system",
      "Education sector",
      "Railway system",
      "Revenue reforms",
    ],
    answer: "Education sector",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The first railway line (1853) in India was introduced by Governor-General —",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Curzon",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Dalhousie",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Governor-General who introduced the Permanent Settlement of Bengal (1793) was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The first Governor-General of Bengal who ended the Dual Government system by enforcing the Regulating Act of 1773 was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Clive",
      "Warren Hastings",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Warren Hastings",
  },

  {
    question: "Doctrine of Lapse in India was introduced by Governor-General —",
    options: [
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Curzon",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Dalhousie",
  },

  {
    question: "The Viceroy of India at the time of India's independence was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Irwin",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The incorporation of English as the official language for higher education in India was done by —",
    options: ["Lord Macaulay", "Lord Cornwallis", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Ripon"],
    answer: "Lord Macaulay",
  },

  {
    question: "The Vernacular Press Act was enacted during the regime of —",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Dalhousie"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Tripartite Treaty for British interference in Afghanistan was signed by —",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Ellenborough",
      "Lord Auckland",
      "Lord Canning",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Auckland",
  },

  {
    question: "The Father of Civil Services in India is —",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Warren Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Frazer Commission was appointed to investigate police administration by —",
    options: ["Lord Curzon", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Dalhousie"],
    answer: "Lord Curzon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Accused of committing the judicial murder of Raja Nand Kumar was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Warren Hastings",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Warren Hastings",
  },

  {
    question: "The Governor-General during the Anglo-Nepal War was —",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Canning",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Hastings",
  },

  {
    question: "Lord Dalhousie annexed Punjab into British India in —",
    options: ["1845", "1846", "1849", "1850"],
    answer: "1849",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lord Dalhousie annexed Punjab into British India as the result of —",
    options: [
      "First Anglo-Sikh War",
      "Second Anglo-Sikh War",
      "Third Anglo-Sikh War",
      "Treaty of Lahore",
    ],
    answer: "Second Anglo-Sikh War",
  },

  {
    question:
      "During the trial for the Meerut conspiracy, the Viceroy of India was —",
    options: ["Lord Irwin", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Linlithgow"],
    answer: "Lord Irwin",
  },

  {
    question: "The Doctrine of Subsidiary Alliance was introduced by —",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Curzon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Wellesley",
  },

  {
    question: "General Dyer was responsible for —",
    options: [
      "Partition of Bengal",
      "Jallianwala Bagh massacre",
      "Salt Satyagraha suppression",
      "Khilafat Movement",
    ],
    answer: "Jallianwala Bagh massacre",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Ryotwari system was devised during British rule in India by —",
    options: [
      "Thomas Munro",
      "Alexander Reed",
      "Charles Metcalfe",
      "Warren Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Alexander Reed",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Zamindari system was introduced during the British rule in India by?",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Colin Mackenzie was appointed as the first Surveyor General of India in which year?",
    options: ["1805", "1810", "1815", "1820"],
    answer: "1815",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which British Governor General adopted the policy of 'Paramountcy'?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Hastings",
  },

  {
    question: "The first state to be annexed under the Doctrine of Lapse was?",
    options: ["Jhansi", "Awadh", "Satara", "Nagpur"],
    answer: "Satara",
  },

  {
    question:
      "How many Presidencies were there in India during the time of Warren Hastings?",
    options: ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    answer: "3 (Bengal, Madras, and Bombay)",
  },

  {
    question: "Lord Ripon was appointed as the Viceroy of India in which year?",
    options: ["1875", "1880", "1885", "1890"],
    answer: "1880",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Bahadur Shah Zafar would be the last Mughal king after his death was declared by whom?",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Governor General Canning",
      "Lord Lytton",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Governor General Canning",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Governor General was associated with the abolition of Thuggee?",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord William Bentinck",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Lord William Bentinck",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Governor General of Bengal during the First Anglo-Maratha War?",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Warren Hastings",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Warren Hastings",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the last Viceroy of India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Irwin",
      "Lord Wavell",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the first Governor General of India after independence?",
    options: [
      "C. Rajagopalachari",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Dr. Rajendra Prasad",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the first Indian Governor-General of independent India?",
    options: [
      "C. Rajagopalachari",
      "Dr. Rajendra Prasad",
      "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    ],
    answer: "C Rajagopalachari",
  },
  {
    question: "The Viceroy of India at the time of the Kakori conspiracy was?",
    options: ["Lord Irwin", "Lord Reading", "Lord Canning", "Lord Mountbatten"],
    answer: "Lord Reading",
  },

  {
    question: "The Viceroy of India during the Dandi March was?",
    options: ["Lord Irwin", "Lord Mountbatten", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Reading"],
    answer: "Lord Irwin",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Bifurcation of British Indian Empire into a secular India and Islamic Pakistan was announced by?",
    options: [
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Irwin",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },

  {
    question:
      "C.P. Ilbert was a law member of the Council under which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Curzon", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Canning"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Governor of Bombay province of India during 1819–1827?",
    options: ["Elphinstone", "Cornwallis", "Wellesley", "Ripon"],
    answer: "Elphinstone",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who designed the administrative code to separate revenue administration from judicial administration?",
    options: ["Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Cornwallis", "Lord Ripon"],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Viceroy took keen interest in the restoration and protection of historical monuments?",
    options: ["Lord Curzon", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Canning"],
    answer: "Lord Curzon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Ancient Monuments Preservation Act was passed in 1904 under which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Reading"],
    answer: "Lord Curzon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who brought the resolution on local self-government for political education in India?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Wellesley"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is known as the Father of Local Self-Government in India?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Canning", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the first Viceroy of India?",
    options: ["Lord Canning", "Lord Mountbatten", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The policy of dual system of Bengal government was the brainchild of which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Clive",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Clive",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The practice of Sati was outlawed by which Governor-General of Bengal?",
    options: [
      "Lord William Bentinck",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord William Bentinck",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the first Governor General of India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "William Bentinck",
      "Warren Hastings",
      "Lord Canning",
    ],
    answer: "William Bentinck",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Governor General described Awadh as ‘a cherry’ ready to be plucked?",
    options: ["Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Canning", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Wellesley"],
    answer: "Lord Dalhousie",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the last Governor General of British India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Canning",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Warren Hastings served as Governor General from which year to which year?",
    options: ["1773 to 1785", "1786 to 1798", "1798 to 1805", "1765 to 1772"],
    answer: "1773 to 1785",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Permanent Settlement of Bengal was introduced in 1793 during the tenure of which Governor General?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1809, Maharaja Ranjit Singh signed the Amritsar Treaty with whom?",
    options: [
      "Charles T. Metcalfe",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Warren Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Charles T. Metcalfe",
  },

  {
    question: "‘A History of British India’ was written by which author?",
    options: [
      "James Mill",
      "Charles Metcalfe",
      "Thomas Macaulay",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "James Mill",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1801, the Subsidiary Alliance treaty was imposed on which state?",
    options: ["Awadh", "Hyderabad", "Mysore", "Nagpur"],
    answer: "Awadh",
  },

  {
    question: "The English Education Act of 1835 was based on which document?",
    options: [
      "Macaulay’s Minute",
      "Charter Act of 1833",
      "Hunter Commission",
      "Wood’s Dispatch",
    ],
    answer: "Macaulay’s Minute",
  },

  {
    question: "The Vernacular Press Act of 1878 was repealed by which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Dalhousie"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1856, which Governor-General decided that Bahadur Shah Zafar would be the last Mughal king?",
    options: ["Lord Canning", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },

  {
    question:
      "During the formation of the Indian National Congress in 1885, who was the Viceroy of India?",
    options: ["Lord Dufferin", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Lytton"],
    answer: "Lord Dufferin",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who took the first step to separate provincial finance from central finance?",
    options: ["Lord Mayo", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Dalhousie"],
    answer: "Lord Mayo",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Financial decentralisation in India was introduced in 1870 by which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Mayo", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Lytton"],
    answer: "Lord Mayo",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is known as the Father of Civil Services in India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Ripon",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Canning",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Daroga system replacing Zamindari Thanedars was introduced by which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Ripon",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question: "At what age did Robert Clive come to Madras from England?",
    options: ["18 years", "21 years", "25 years", "15 years"],
    answer: "18 years",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The East India Company started appointing Residents in Indian states after which battle?",
    options: [
      "Battle of Buxar (1764)",
      "Battle of Plassey (1757)",
      "Battle of Panipat",
      "Battle of Seringapatam",
    ],
    answer: "Battle of Buxar (1764)",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Richard Wellesley served as Governor General of India during which period?",
    options: ["1798 to 1805", "1786 to 1793", "1805 to 1810", "1765 to 1772"],
    answer: "1798 to 1805",
  },

  {
    question: "The infamous 'Crawling Order' was issued by whom?",
    options: ["General Dyer", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Irwin"],
    answer: "General Dyer",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the Viceroy of India during the Bengal Famine of 1943?",
    options: [
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Reading",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Linlithgow",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The first medical college in India was established during the period of which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Lord William Bentinck",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord William Bentinck",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Viceroy of British India when the Rowlatt Act was passed?",
    options: [
      "Lord Chelmsford",
      "Lord Irwin",
      "Lord Curzon",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Chelmsford",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is known as the Father of Local Self-Government in India?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Wellesley"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the last Viceroy of India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Reading",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Lord Dalhousie served as Governor General of India during which period?",
    options: ["1848 to 1856", "1833 to 1842", "1856 to 1862", "1820 to 1830"],
    answer: "1848 to 1856",
  },

  {
    question: "Who announced the transfer of power to Indians by June 1948?",
    options: [
      "Clement Attlee",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
    ],
    answer: "Clement Attlee",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Governor General described the Kingdom of Awadh as ‘a cherry that will drop into our mouth one day’?",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Dalhousie",
  },

  {
    question:
      "During whose viceroyalty did the Jallianwala Bagh massacre take place?",
    options: [
      "Lord Chelmsford",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Irwin",
      "Lord Lytton",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Chelmsford",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Royal Commission on Civil Services was formed in 1912 during whose viceroyship?",
    options: ["Lord Hardinge", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Chelmsford"],
    answer: "Lord Hardinge",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Madras Presidency was formed during the tenure of which Governor General?",
    options: [
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Wellesley",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lord Wellesley built a massive palace, Government House, for himself in which city?",
    options: ["Calcutta", "Madras", "Delhi", "Bombay"],
    answer: "Calcutta",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the last Governor-General and first Viceroy of India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Under which Governor-General was the policy of ‘paramountcy’ initiated?",
    options: [
      "Lord Hastings",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Hastings",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Viceroy of British India when India became independent in 1947?",
    options: [
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Chelmsford",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mountbatten",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is known as the ‘Father of Civil Services’ in India?",
    options: [
      "Charles Cornwallis",
      "Lord Ripon",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Curzon",
    ],
    answer: "Charles Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1939, which Viceroy of India announced that India had entered World War II along with Britain?",
    options: [
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Wavell",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Lord Irwin",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Linlithgow",
  },

  {
    question: "Who organised the Statistical Survey of India?",
    options: ["Lord Mayo", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Cornwallis"],
    answer: "Lord Mayo",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Permanent Settlement of Bengal was introduced in 1793 under which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Charles Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Charles Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is known as the ‘Father of Communal Electorate’ in India?",
    options: ["Lord Minto", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon"],
    answer: "Lord Minto",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Vernacular Press Act in India was introduced by which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Office of Governor-General of India was created by which Act?",
    options: [
      "Charter Act, 1833",
      "Regulating Act, 1773",
      "Pitt’s India Act, 1784",
      "Government of India Act, 1858",
    ],
    answer: "Charter Act, 1833",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1946, who was invited by Lord Wavell to form the interim Government of India?",
    options: [
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "Sardar Patel",
      "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
    ],
    answer: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the last Governor General of India from 1948 to 1950?",
    options: [
      "C. Rajagopalachari",
      "Lord Mountbatten",
      "Dr. Rajendra Prasad",
      "Lord Wavell",
    ],
    answer: "C. Rajagopalachari",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was called the ‘Liberator of the Indian Press’?",
    options: ["Charles Metcalfe", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Charles Metcalfe",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lord Curzon was appointed as the Viceroy of India in which year?",
    options: ["1899", "1885", "1905", "1910"],
    answer: "1899",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Permanent Settlement system in 1793 was introduced by which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The law against the practice of Sati in December 1829 was enacted by which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Lord William Bentinck",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord William Bentinck",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Vernacular Press Act of 1878 was introduced by which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Dalhousie"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },
  {
    question: "Vernacular Press Act of 1878 was repealed by whom?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Mayo"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question: "Who introduced the Doctrine of Lapse in India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Dalhousie",
  },

  {
    question: "Who withdrew the Doctrine of Lapse?",
    options: ["Lord Canning", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Wellesley"],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In which year did the Mughal Emperor appoint the East India Company as the Diwan of Bengal?",
    options: ["1765", "1757", "1773", "1784"],
    answer: "1765",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Maharaja Chait Singh of Banaras was arrested by Warren Hastings in which year?",
    options: ["1781", "1773", "1785", "1764"],
    answer: "1781",
  },

  {
    question: "Robert Clive first came to India in which year?",
    options: ["1743", "1757", "1765", "1773"],
    answer: "1743",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who conferred the title 'Kaiser-i-Hind' on Queen Victoria in Delhi Durbar?",
    options: ["Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Canning"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lord Cornwallis served as the Governor-General of Bengal during which years?",
    options: ["1786 to 1793", "1773 to 1785", "1798 to 1805", "1848 to 1856"],
    answer: "1786 to 1793",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who introduced the Permanent Settlement and civil services in India?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question: "The Hunter Commission (1882) was appointed by which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Mayo", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question: "The 'August Offer' was made by Lord Linlithgow in which year?",
    options: ["1940", "1942", "1939", "1945"],
    answer: "1940",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the first Governor-General of Bengal?",
    options: [
      "Warren Hastings",
      "Robert Clive",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Warren Hastings",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Governor-General of Bengal was made the Governor-General of India under which Act?",
    options: [
      "Charter Act of 1833",
      "Pitt’s India Act 1784",
      "Regulating Act 1773",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Charter Act of 1833",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Governor-General of India during the First World War?",
    options: [
      "Lord Hardinge II",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Chelmsford",
      "Lord Curzon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Hardinge II",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who introduced the code separating revenue administration from judicial administration?",
    options: [
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Canning",
      "Lord Ripon",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Cornwallis",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The title of 'Viceroy' was first used for the Governor-General of India in which year?",
    options: ["1858", "1833", "1773", "1793"],
    answer: "1858",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Governor-General of India during the First Anglo-Sikh War (1845–46)?",
    options: [
      "Lord Hardinge",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Lord Hastings",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Hardinge",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is known as the Father of Local Self-Government in India?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Mayo", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Cornwallis"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Viceroy first shifted his council officially to Shimla during summer?",
    options: ["John Lawrence", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Ripon"],
    answer: "John Lawrence",
  },

  {
    question: "Who started the Indian Agriculture Service?",
    options: ["Lord Minto II", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Mayo"],
    answer: "Lord Minto II",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Governor-General of India was impeached by the British Parliament?",
    options: [
      "Warren Hastings",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
    ],
    answer: "Warren Hastings",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the Viceroy of India at the time of Gandhiji’s Dandi March?",
    options: [
      "Lord Irwin",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
      "Lord Chelmsford",
      "Lord Hardinge",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Irwin",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Ilbert Bill (1883) was proposed during the tenure of which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Mayo"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question: "Who introduced the Vernacular Press Act in India?",
    options: ["Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Mayo"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },

  {
    question: "Who repealed the Vernacular Press Act in India?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Mayo"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },
  {
    question: "Lord Mayo’s Resolution of 1870 was an attempt to rectify what?",
    options: [
      "Existing imparity",
      "Revenue collection errors",
      "Judicial bias",
      "Trade imbalance",
    ],
    answer: "Existing imparity",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The first step that bifurcated Central and Provincial finances was taken under which resolution?",
    options: [
      "Lord Mayo’s Resolution of 1870",
      "Lord Ripon’s Resolution of 1882",
      "Charter Act of 1833",
      "Government of India Act 1858",
    ],
    answer: "Lord Mayo’s Resolution of 1870",
  },

  {
    question: "Who introduced the system of Mahalwari settlement in Bengal?",
    options: [
      "Holt Mackenzie",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Thomas Munro",
      "Charles Metcalfe",
    ],
    answer: "Holt Mackenzie",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the first British Governor of Bihar?",
    options: [
      "Sir James David Sifton",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Wellesley",
      "Robert Clive",
    ],
    answer: "Sir James David Sifton",
  },

  {
    question: "Sind was conquered and annexed by whom?",
    options: ["Napier", "Dalhousie", "Cornwallis", "Wellesley"],
    answer: "Napier",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Viceroy followed an aggressive policy towards Afghanistan?",
    options: ["Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Under which system were Zamindars granted legal ownership of land in exchange for fixed revenue payments?",
    options: [
      "Permanent Settlement",
      "Ryotwari System",
      "Mahalwari System",
      "Jagirdari System",
    ],
    answer: "Permanent Settlement",
  },

  {
    question: "In which year did Lord Lytton pass the Indian Arms Act?",
    options: ["1878", "1872", "1858", "1885"],
    answer: "1878",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Arms Act, 1878 and Vernacular Press Act, 1878 were passed under which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Lytton", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Mayo", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Lytton",
  },

  {
    question: "In which year was the Native Marriage Act passed?",
    options: ["1872", "1850", "1829", "1882"],
    answer: "1872",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Vernacular Press Act of 1878 was modelled on which country’s press laws?",
    options: [
      "Irish Press Laws",
      "British Press Laws",
      "French Press Laws",
      "American Press Laws",
    ],
    answer: "Irish Press Laws",
  },

  {
    question: "The Defence of India Act was enacted in which year?",
    options: ["1915", "1919", "1935", "1942"],
    answer: "1915",
  },

  {
    question: "The Rowlatt Act was passed in which year?",
    options: ["1919", "1915", "1920", "1935"],
    answer: "1919",
  },

  {
    question: "The Criminal Tribes Act was passed in which year?",
    options: ["1871", "1850", "1882", "1878"],
    answer: "1871",
  },

  {
    question: "The Bengal Sati Regulation Act was passed in which year?",
    options: ["1829", "1833", "1850", "1872"],
    answer: "1829",
  },

  {
    question: "The Caste Disabilities Removal Act was passed in which year?",
    options: ["1850", "1829", "1872", "1885"],
    answer: "1850",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the first Viceroy of India?",
    options: ["Lord Canning", "Lord Dalhousie", "Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon"],
    answer: "Lord Canning",
  },

  {
    question:
      "According to the Indian Independence Act 1947, British rule in India would end by which date?",
    options: [
      "30 June 1948",
      "15 August 1947",
      "1 January 1948",
      "26 January 1950",
    ],
    answer: "30 June 1948",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The powers between Central and Provincial governments through three lists were divided by which Act?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act of 1935",
      "Charter Act of 1833",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
      "Regulating Act 1773",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act of 1935",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lord Cornwallis initiated the Permanent Settlement system in which regions?",
    options: [
      "Bengal and Bihar",
      "Punjab and Awadh",
      "Bombay and Madras",
      "Sindh and Assam",
    ],
    answer: "Bengal and Bihar",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Act abolished the rule of the East India Company and the Board of Control?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1858",
      "Charter Act 1833",
      "Regulating Act 1773",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1858",
  },

  {
    question: "Which Act centralized the administration of India?",
    options: [
      "Charter Act of 1833",
      "Regulating Act 1773",
      "Government of India Act 1858",
      "Pitt’s India Act 1784",
    ],
    answer: "Charter Act of 1833",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Jhansi was annexed by Lord Dalhousie under the Doctrine of Lapse in which year?",
    options: ["1854", "1856", "1848", "1850"],
    answer: "1854",
  },
  {
    question: "In which year was Awadh annexed by the British?",
    options: ["1856", "1854", "1857", "1860"],
    answer: "1856",
  },

  {
    question:
      "In 1877, Viceroy Lytton organised a durbar to acknowledge Queen Victoria as the?",
    options: [
      "Empress of India",
      "Queen of Britain",
      "Sovereign of India",
      "Supreme Ruler of India",
    ],
    answer: "Empress of India",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Elizabeth I granted the East India Company exclusive East Asian trading rights in which year?",
    options: ["1600", "1610", "1595", "1620"],
    answer: "1600",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The first Factories Act was enacted during Lord Ripon's time in which year?",
    options: ["1881", "1872", "1890", "1885"],
    answer: "1881",
  },

  {
    question: "Who introduced the Mahalwari system in India?",
    options: [
      "Holt Mackenzie",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Sir Thomas Munro",
    ],
    answer: "Holt Mackenzie",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Mahalwari system was introduced during the period of which Governor-General?",
    options: [
      "Lord William Bentinck",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
      "Lord Ripon",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
    ],
    answer: "Lord William Bentinck",
  },

  {
    question:
      "British Parliament transferred powers to the Crown from the East India Company through which Act?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1858",
      "Charter Act 1833",
      "Regulating Act 1773",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1858",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Act allowed some elected representation in the legislature for the first time?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1909",
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
      "Charter Act 1833",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1909",
  },

  {
    question: "The Government of India Act 1909 is also known as?",
    options: [
      "Morley-Minto Reforms",
      "Montagu-Chelmsford Reforms",
      "Minto-Morley Reforms",
      "Indian Councils Act",
    ],
    answer: "Morley-Minto Reforms",
  },

  {
    question: "The Morley-Minto Reforms of 1909 aimed to implement what?",
    options: [
      "Separate electoral system",
      "Centralized administration",
      "Dyarchy rule",
      "Provincial autonomy",
    ],
    answer: "Separate electoral system",
  },

  {
    question: "Which Act granted autonomy to the provinces in India?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Government of India Act 1909",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
      "Charter Act 1833",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1935",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Government of India Act 1935 came into effect in which year?",
    options: ["1937", "1935", "1939", "1940"],
    answer: "1937",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Major portions of the Indian Constitution were borrowed from which Act?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Government of India Act 1909",
      "Charter Act 1833",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1935",
  },

  {
    question: "The Constitution of India superseded which Act?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Government of India Act 1909",
      "Charter Act 1833",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1935",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The establishment of a Federal Court in Delhi was provided by which Act?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Government of India Act 1909",
      "Charter Act 1833",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1935",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The dyarchy rule system in the provinces was abolished by which Act?",
    options: [
      "Government of India Act 1935",
      "Government of India Act 1909",
      "Montagu-Chelmsford Reforms",
      "Indian Councils Act 1861",
    ],
    answer: "Government of India Act 1935",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the head of the Indian Statutory Commission (Simon Commission) of 1928?",
    options: [
      "Sir John Allsebrook Simon",
      "Lord Ripon",
      "Lord Chelmsford",
      "Lord Linlithgow",
    ],
    answer: "Sir John Allsebrook Simon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Majority Act, defining the age of majority for Indian citizens, was passed in which year?",
    options: ["1875", "1872", "1882", "1850"],
    answer: "1875",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Indian Education Commission of 1882 was appointed by which Viceroy?",
    options: ["Lord Ripon", "Lord Curzon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Mayo"],
    answer: "Lord Ripon",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Saddler Commission, to analyze Calcutta University’s problems, was appointed in which year?",
    options: ["1917", "1882", "1902", "1920"],
    answer: "1917",
  },

  {
    question: "Who introduced the Ryotwari system in India?",
    options: [
      "Sir Thomas Munro",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Holt Mackenzie",
      "Lord Dalhousie",
    ],
    answer: "Sir Thomas Munro",
  },

  {
    question: "The Ryotwari system was based on which theory?",
    options: [
      "Ricardian theory of rent",
      "Labour theory of value",
      "Marginal utility theory",
      "Physiocratic theory",
    ],
    answer: "Ricardian theory of rent",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Secretary of State for India became responsible for the Government of British India in which year?",
    options: ["1858", "1833", "1773", "1861"],
    answer: "1858",
  },
];
